Like a silent disease slowly
but surely ravaging the body,
an evil is lurking
a midst our streets, in our Morioh,
claiming more lives
in more unknown locations.
What's worse, the killings
have gone completely unnoticed
It's shocking.
It's downright chilling.
But we have no way of
finding the killer.
Even the number of
Stand users in Morioh is a mystery
People aren't worried about
some silent killer…
They're worried about
what's for dinner,
they're blind to those happenings
outside their immediate view.
KAMEYU
TRANSACTION NO. BANK NO.
BRANCH NO. WINDOW NO.
DEPOSIT AMOUNT BALANCE
I have 285 yen to my name?!
I had 20,000 yen in savings!
Twelve yen?!
I have no willpower!
That 20,000 yen was
for those dope designer shoes…
What the hell did I even buy?
This is all
that crusty old fart's fault!
He charged 130,000 yen worth of
baby bullshit to my freak in card!
I did have the old man
pay me back the 130,000,
then I got bit by
this mysterious spending bug…
and my money sense
flew out the window.
Maybe there's a thousand yen
somewhere that I forgot about.
A roach!
Guess a bank's no different
from anywhere else.
A S-Stand?
Got one yen.
Little bastard!
I-It's a Stand!
We have ourselves
a new Stand on our hands!
JOJO'S BIZARRE ADVENTURE
DIAMOND IS UNBREAKABLE
A demon's crept into
our everyday life
It's about to take away
something precious
Our peace has already
crumbled long ago
So casually, so nonchalantly
It's taken from us
before we know it
If we want it back,
now's the chance
With the sharpness of
the piercing arrow
The beauty of two souls united
Wherever you go, chase you
Whenever, chase you
I will chase you
Nowhere to escape
Start running, I will chase you
Tomorrow, chase you
My fists will be the one
to show you
Tenacity decides
who will win or lose
So I chase you
EPISODE 18
SHIGECHI'S HARVEST, PART 1
Where the hell is he running?
Another one!
Damn it! What the hell are you?!
I'll slaughter you!
Okuyasu!
Oh, Josuke!
Look! An enemy Stand.
I'm gonna squash him to death!
There are two of 'em!
Yeah. I followed one of 'em
all the way from the bank.
How'd he attack you?
Well, he didn't really attack me.
I was buying some Calpis Water,
when suddenly he popped out from
under the vending machine.
What? So you weren't attacked?
You just said
you'll slaughter the little guy.
The little pest startled me
so much,
I spilled Calpis Water
all over my uniform.
Damn it! Give me back my money!
Got it!
Hey, another one joined the pack…
Got it. Got it.
What the… What are these things?
There's so many of them!
They're a little army!
Okuyasu, they're like
your brother Keicho's Stand.
But…
The way they're completely
ignoring us is kinda eerie.
Yeah…
Watch out!
The user's nearby… probably.
BOOM
It's…
It's money!
You know, it did swipe a 1 yen coin
from underneath the atm
at the bank.
It's just a bunch of
1 yen and 10 yen coins,
but they're the real deal!
Good pickings, everyone.
A yen saved is a yen earned.
I think that makes about
five thousand yen.
As long as I have Harvest
by my side,
I'll be set for life.
Hey, looks like that's the user.
He's talking to his Stand…
Yeah… Looks like he's another
product of the bow and arrow.
But it doesn't seem
like he wants to hurt us.
Grin!
You guys…
You can see Harvest?
You really can see it, right?!
Yeah, it's called a Stand.
I'm Josuke Higashikata.
This is Okuyasu Nijimura.
So we're friends!
My first friends!
My name is Shigekiyo Yangu.
I'm an eighth-grader
at Budogaoka Middle School.
I weigh 110 kilograms.
My mommy and daddy
call me "Shigechi."
First it was "Shige-chan,"
then "Shigechi."
I have a pet turtle named Gonta.
The other day, I wanted to see
if the 41 yen, 62 yen,
and 150 yen stamps
tasted different,
so I licked them a lot,
and Mommy yelled at me.
This is a picture of my Mommy.
She yelled at me.
A picture…
Wow, your mom's pretty hot.
Weird.
U-Um…
So, these things are "Harvest"?
Did they really pick up
all these coins?
Yeah. They got 'em from ditches and
the bottom of vending machines…
But I'm not a robber.
The koban policeman said…
"for coin denominations
less than one hundred yen,
no return is necessary."
I hate bad things!
There's nothing bad
about that at all!
In fact, I think
you're doing society a favor.
It's no boatload of cash,
but you're taking forgotten funds
and reinjecting it into
the Japanese economy.
You're doing a great thing.
Really? You think it's great?
Hey, do you think I'm great?
Talk about hidden in plain sight.
No one would ever think of
collecting money like this.
I'm jealous… You're smart.
D-Did you just say I was smart?
N-No one's ever said that
to me before.
I've picked up about
120,000 yen, but…
120,000?!
B-But your words make me
even happier!
A t-total of 120,000?!
Pretty good, right?
J-Just from Morioh?
Yes sir! I never leave Morioh.
I'd get lost and someone
could take me away.
120,000… And I have a measly 12.
Okuyasu…
What's with your left foot?
Whoa, what the…
Who would a thought there'd be
three 50 yen coins over here!
Could they belong to Shigekiyo?
I didn't even see them…
Sneaky bastard…
Here, I'll give you guys half.
Huh?!
We're friends, right?
We can do the same kind of stuff.
R-Really?!
Lucky us!
N-No… Wait.
Look, you can't just simply
hand over money and stuff.
Okay, then I'll put some
real effort into it.
It's all yours.
We're friends, right?
Hey, why are you
making your face all strained?
H-Hey…
Excuse us for a moment while
we have a quick chat, Shigechi.
Listen, Josuke!
Enough of the do-gooder shit, okay?
If he wants to give us the money,
then we take it, dumb-ass!
My pride won't let me do that.
Not this man.
As long as it's not some disease,
I'll take whatever damned thing
someone wants to give me! Got it?!
Take a chill pill!
I getcha, I getcha!
Stop crying!
But…
I am pretty strapped for cash, too.
Which is why I just thought of
a nice little idea
that'll make everyone happy.
Huh? An idea that'll make
everyone happy?
You just leave it to me.
HARVEST
THE PARK IS FOR POLITE CHILDREN
WHO GET ALONG WITH OTHERS
MORIOH CITY
Hey, Shigekiyo.
Can I call you "Shigechi"?
Sure.
Shigechi, we can't
accept your money.
What you were trying to do just now
is no different from trying to
buy your way into friendship.
Huh? B-But I wasn't
trying to do that!
If you ask me,
friendship is something you build.
All I wanted was to…
I know. And I know how you feel.
We Stand users are a team.
And so…
Why don't we build our friendship
with a little business?
Business?
Yeah. Us three putting our heads
together to make a little dough.
You mean this?
No "dough," not "elbow."
What I mean is,
there's only so much money you can
make by picking up leftover change.
I have a more lucrative approach
in mind for Harvest.
Huh?
You have a better idea
than picking up change?
Nothing corrupt about it,
and it won't inconvenience
a single soul.
What kind of idea?
That's where the business part
comes in!
For coming up with the idea,
you can give Okuyasu and me
half of the profits.
The other half goes to you,
Shigechi.
The three of us are going to work
together and pull this thing off.
It'll be a win-win for all of us.
O-Okay! So what do I get to do?
You know what this is, right?
KAMEYU
A b-blue stamp!
You got it!
That sticker you get with every
100 yen purchase from Kameyu,
one of eastern Japan's
biggest department stores.
And I'm pretty sure there are
a bunch of people
who just toss 'em.
Then there's these.
PRODUCT VOUCHER
20 YEN
MEIWADO STATIONERY
A 20-yen voucher from
Meiwado, that stationary store.
OSCAR
A voucher from CD Shop Oscar,
ten will get you
2,000 yen worth of merchandise.
NAGASAKI CLEANERS
YOTSUBA ELECTRONICS
The cleaners,
Märchen Kids toy store…
SERVICE CARD
and this is a card from
Yotsuba Electronics.
Now, this is the important part.
With some, like at Kameyu,
you can get cash back.
Ah, you mean… I got it, Josuke!
I see what you're getting at!
Everyone, it's time!
RUMBLE
One or two might be
worthless scraps of paper…
But picking up
the tens of thousands
of ones lying around town
with Harvest…
Got it.
This trash can!
Now that one!
Got it. Got it.
Got it.
Got it. Got it. Got it.
Th-They just keep piling up!
Your Stand's amazing!
Amazing, Shigechi!
Wow, another compliment.
I'll fix the torn ones
with Shining Diamond.
Yes! We must have
thousands of them now.
No, we must have over 100,000.
Yes!
GRAB
To the unbeatable trio!
Let's go cash in!
But, Josuke,
you sure are a smooth talker.
Pride my ass…
Everyone's gonna be happy.
It's all good.
F-Friendship is neat…
O-Okuyasu, J-Josuke,
will it be okay?
You can turn them into money
that easily?
Relax, Shigechi.
Give Josuke a chance.
It's Okuyasu and…
Who is that?
Okuyasu—
Josuke! H-How'd it go?
Did you get our money?
Did they tell you to piss off?
The CD shop and toy store
don't do cash back.
But we can exchange the coupons
for about 40,000 yen worth of
CDs and video games.
Forget about that!
What about Kameyu?
Didja get cash for
the Kameyu stickers?
Well, something kind of
unexpected happened.
S-Something unexpected?
It unexpectedly
turned into 61,500 yen!
Behold!
The genuine article, Shigechi!
I-It's real!
Real cash right before my eyes!
It's like a dream!
Amazeballs, Shigechi!
Your Stand, Harvest,
is totally amazing!
Y-You really think it's amazing?
Hey… Nobody ever
really compliments me…
Do you really think I'm amazing?
Hey, have a little more confidence,
Shigechi.
You can do something
no one else can.
Okuyasu… Josuke…
All right.
Hey, doll face.
I got a wad of greenbacks
just waiting to be spent!
Wanna have some fun?
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Oh, yeah. Here, Josuke, Okuyasu.
Here's your share, 10,000 yen.
Shigechi, what is this?
We're comrades… Friends, right?
Yeah, we're a team.
And that's a token
of our friendship.
Hey, wait…
This isn't what we agreed,
Shigechi.
You said half would go to us.
Half of 61,500 yen is 30,750.
R-Really? Did I say that?
What?
Besides…
It w-was my H-Harvest
that did all the collecting.
I did it all!
Y-You guys are all talk
and no action.
Well if Josuke hadn't come up
with the idea,
you would've never thought of
picking up those stupid tickets!
Eventually I would have!
I'm amazing, remember?!
Wrong… No way that cantaloupe
of a noggin
would've ever thought of
something like that!
Hey, stop, Okuyasu.
Easy there, big guy.
This is just great.
He was happy to give us
a few thousand,
but suddenly handing over a few
ten thousands is crossing the line.
He doesn't mean any harm,
but he's got the mind of a kid.
No matter what we say,
it's gonna feel like
we tricked him.
We should be the adults here
and call it a day.
We got 10,000 yen out of it,
and that's good enough.
Well, I guess if you
put it like that…
But he really rubs me
the wrong way!
You sure he's not pulling
a fast one on us?
No, Okuyasu, fighting's not gonna
get us anywhere now.
We just need to school Shigechi
on what a contract between
mature adults really means.
To put a little more jingle
in your pocket?
You fickle bastard…
And that's what I love about you.
All right, we'll gladly take this.
Okuyasu.
Are you thirsty?
Anything you want to drink?
I'll buy.
You're gonna treat me?
Then… make it a Calpis Water.
Then drink some.
Ah! Hey! Why are you
throwing those away?
They're just worthless junk,
like year-end lottery tickets.
I told Shigechi to pick them up
with the other tickets.
You mean these losing New Year's
postcard lottery letters?
How do you know
they're losing tickets?
No one throw's away
a winning ticket, dumb-ass.
Hey, plenty of people forget to
check their numbers
and miss out on
claiming their prizes!
If this wins,
I'm gonna take half of it.
Now promise me, dammit.
Fine. Half it is.
But if you win a sheet of stamps,
you can have it.
EXCITING
WINNING NUMBERS
You really like those cheap
little gambling games, dontcha?
No good… How 'bout this…
I wonder if I can collect
lottery prizes if
I'm still in high school.
Lottery?
As long as you have your ID
and name stamp, it should be fine.
SG GROUP
PAYOUT PERIOD
FROM 1/20/1999
TO 6/21/1999
Nope, another dud.
I thought I had a chance, but…
Hm?
3RD
SG GROUP
BT GROUP
SG Group 121314… Um…
Hey, um if,
if by any chance I won…
Would I have to take it
to the police?
You idiot.
Why would you turn it in to them?
Harvest picked up
only what people threw away.
Worry about winning first,
okay, big man?
Best of luck.
What? SG Group 121314?!
SG GROUP
PAYOUT PERIOD
FROM 1/20/1999
TO 6/21/1999
SG Group 121314?!
WINNING NUMBERS
LIST
SG Group 121314!
Hey, what are you roaring about?
PRIZE 5 MILLION YEN
5 MILLION YEN
5,000,000!
There's no question! I won!
What?! This better not
be some stupid-ass joke!
5 MILLION YEN
Yes! It's a dream come true!
No one in the world has ever
experienced something like this!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
Settle down, Okuyasu.
Let's just double check
to make sure.
SG Group 121314,
prize 5,000,000 yen.
It's undeniable!
It's seems too good to be true,
but it isn't!
Some old, discarded lottery ticket,
bound for the incinerator.
It expires in a few days.
If they try to ask us a bunch
of pesky questions at the bank,
we say we bought it
fair and square!
Got it?
You bet I do!
Which means
it's our 5,000,000 yen!
Now what should I buy…
First, I'm gonna buy
me some sick Italian shoes!
Then a designer suit
that complements my sleek lines.
Then it's on to Tonio's for
the most expensive food he's got!
And I've gotta take
a trip overseas!
Mine goes in savings!
Live your own sucky life!
My Harvest did all the work…
Five million…
Th-That money stays with me…
all of it.
EPISODE 19
SHIGECHI'S HARVEST, PART 2